One adventure will change two worlds.
How to Train Your Dragon is a fantasy, adventure,
animation film directed by Dean DeBlois.
As the son of a Viking leader on the cusp of manhood, shy Hiccup Horrendous Haddock III
faces a rite of passage: he must kill a dragon to prove his warrior mettle.
But after downing a feared dragon, he realizes that he no longer wants to destroy it, and instead
befriends the beast – which he names Toothless – much to the chagrin of his warrior father.
Hiccup (voice), played by Jay Baruchel.
Stoick (voice), played by Gerard Butler.
Gobber (voice), played by Craig Ferguson.
Astrid (voice), played by America Ferrera.
Snotlout (voice), played by Jonah Hill.
Fishlegs (voice), played by Christopher Mintz-Plasse.
How to Train Your Dragon is a 2010 American animated fantasy film directed by Chris Sanders and Dean DeBlois
and written by Sanders, DeBlois and Will Davies, based on the 2003 novel by Cressida Cowell.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, the film stars the voices of Jay Baruchel, Gerard Butler, Craig
Ferguson, America Ferrera, Jonah Hill, Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Kristen Wiig and T.J.
The story takes place in Berk, a mythical Viking village.
Hiccup, an undersized teen outcast and son of the village chieftain, wishing to become a dragon slayer like
the other Vikings, injures a rare Night Fury dragon but is unable to bring himself to kill it.
He instead helps and befriends the dragon, and quickly discovers that things are not
exactly as they seem in the conflict between Vikings and dragons.
In 2004, the book series began attracting the attention
of executives at DreamWorks Animation.
After the success of Over the Hedge (2006), producer Bonnie Arnold
became interested in the newly acquired property.
The directors of the film wanted to ensure they took advantage of the improvisation abilities of
the secondary cast by frequently bringing them together in the recording sessions.
The filmmakers hired cinematographer Roger Deakins as a visual consultant to help
them with the aesthetics of the film and to add a live-action feel.
John Powell composed the film's musical score.
How to Train Your Dragon premiered at the Gibson Amphitheater on March 21, 2010, and
was released in the United States on March 26 by Paramount Pictures.
The film was a commercial success, earning $495 million and
becoming the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2010.
It received critical acclaim, with praise for its
animation, writing, and 3D sequences.
It received numerous accolades, including two Academy Award nominations, and spawned a a multimedia franchise, including
two sequels, How to Train Your Dragon 2 (2014) and How to Train Your Dragon: The Hidden World (2019).
A live-action remake was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of friendship, ship,
blacksmith, island, based on novel or book.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting.